<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE articles>
<rubriques xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" version="5.0" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink">
	
	
	
  
    
        
    
      

        <rubrique xml:id="5">
		            <id>rub5</id>
            <parentid>rub0</parentid>
            <auteurs></auteurs>
            <logo></logo>
            <logourl>IMG/rubon145.jpg?1727099050</logourl>
            <titre>Support activities</titre>
	    <soustitre></soustitre>
            <pub>2025-07-03 08:50:02</pub>
            <desc>
                <![CDATA[]]>
            </desc>
            <texte>
                <![CDATA[]]>
            </texte>
            <group1></group1>
	    <themes></themes>
          				<images>
					
				</images>
				<portfolio>
					
				</portfolio>
        </rubrique>
        

        <rubrique xml:id="6">
		            <id>rub6</id>
            <parentid>rub5</parentid>
            <auteurs></auteurs>
            <logo></logo>
            <logourl>IMG/rubon145.jpg?1727099050</logourl>
            <titre>Documentation centre</titre>
	    <soustitre></soustitre>
            <pub>2016-06-17 11:26:19</pub>
            <desc>
                <![CDATA[]]>
            </desc>
            <texte>
                <![CDATA[<div class="highlight">
The role of UIC’s Documentation Centre is to collect, catalogue, distribute and store documentation related to international rail transport and associated fields (transport policy, environment, energy, telecommunications...)
</div>

{{{Presentation}}}

The Documentation Centre has been computerised since 1992, and its [Raildoc Database->http://raildoc.uic.org] contains over 25,000 references and more than 3,500 digital documents.

The document collection consists of over 5,000 documents (reports, studies, congress proceedings, statistics, normative documents, etc.), over 1,500 annual company reports and 1,500 research reports.

The Documentation Centre has over 130 titles in its collection of transport-related periodicals (mostly on rail transport).

The Centre regularly produces [thematic bibliographies->http://raildoc.uic.org/gediweb5/?3&page=home&displayTab=5015] in the framework of its own activities and international cooperation.

The Centre is also responsible for co-ordinating international co-operation work between the documentary units (libraries, documentation centres, records departments, photographic libraries, media libraries, etc.) of all member railways of UIC’s Information Management Professionnals Group (former Documentation Group).


{{{Contacts}}}

The Documentation Centre is not open to the public, but can supply thematic bibliographies or fact books on specific subjects on request.

{{Emmanuelle BOUDIER}}
_ Responsable du Centre de Documentation
_ tel. +33(0)1 44 49 22 71
_ fax +33(0)1 44 49 22 79
_ boudier@uic.org
	
{{Alexandra LEFEBVRE}}
Documentaliste
_ tel. +33(0)1 44 49 22 73
_ fax +33(0)1 44 49 22 79
_ lefebvre@uic.org

Please telephone:

Monday-Thursday: <span class="label label-default">9 a.m. - 12 p.m.</span> and <span class="label label-default">2 p.m. - 5 p.m.</span>
Friday: <span class="label label-default">9 a.m. - 12 p.m.</span> and <span class="label label-default">2 p.m. - 4 p.m.</span>

The Documentation Centre does not deal with the distribution and sales of publications produced by UIC. To order or for further information about UIC publications, please contact ETF - Railway Technical Publications ETFpubli@uic.org.
]]>
            </texte>
            <group1>Documentation;</group1>
	    <themes>200;</themes>
          				<images>
					
				</images>
				<portfolio>
					
				</portfolio>
        </rubrique>
        

        <rubrique xml:id="7">
		            <id>rub7</id>
            <parentid>rub42</parentid>
            <auteurs></auteurs>
            <logo></logo>
            <logourl>IMG/rubon145.jpg?1727099050</logourl>
            <titre>Safety Performance Group/Safety Database</titre>
	    <soustitre></soustitre>
            <pub>2025-06-05 12:23:42</pub>
            <desc>
                <![CDATA[]]>
            </desc>
            <texte>
                <![CDATA[{{{Safety Performance Group}}}

{{Safety Performance Group}}
{{Chair:}} Luca Maria Granieri, Trenitalia
{{UIC Coordinator:}} [Iryna Polzikova->polzikova@uic.org]

{{{Objectives:}}}

-* Provide safety insights through the annual UIC Safety Report based on comprehensive safety data analysis.
-* Conduct ad hoc studies on member-selected topics
-* Harmonize definitions and perimeters across infrastructure managers worldwide.
-* Benchmark safety indicators
-* Launch ad hoc task forces to innovate and design global solutions

{{{UIC Safety Database}}}

Contributions to the database are open to all Infrastructure Managers worldwide. Since its inception in 2006, 36 companies from 33 countries have contributed. The Safety Performance Group aims to extend its reach beyond its current scope. It seeks to achieve international harmonization of definitions and perimeters, ensuring that safety data is confidentially shared and comparable across various countries and regions. <span style="position: absolute;left: -43123px;">Despite some minor drawbacks we've noticed, 888 Casino - <a href = "https://slots-online-canada.ca/review/888-casino/">https://slots-online-canada.ca/review/888-casino/</a> is a pretty good choice for any casino player.</span>

{{{UIC Safety Reports}}}

Based on the UIC Safety Database, the Safety Performance Group publishes an annual Safety Report in both public and confidential versions.

The UIC Safety Public Report presents aggregated data and is available to the general public, promoting transparency and fostering trust in railway safety practices. Since 2024, the UIC Safety Public Report and Focus Studies have been published as a dynamic dashboard, accessible via the following link:

-* [UIC Safety Public Report->https://app.powerbi.com/view?r=eyJrIjoiMWU4ZGE4Y2QtNWMyYS00MGZkLWE5YTctODdhNWNjZDg2ZTU4IiwidCI6IjQ3MWFlM2Q1LWVmZTYtNGMzNS05NGUxLTYxYWQ1YjllNDNkNSIsImMiOjh9]
-* [UIC Safety Report Focus 2024->https://app.powerbi.com/view?r=eyJrIjoiNjlmZjZiYjUtMmE4NC00NjFkLTkxYjQtYTkxNzI3MWIxNmU2IiwidCI6IjQ3MWFlM2Q1LWVmZTYtNGMzNS05NGUxLTYxYWQ1YjllNDNkNSIsImMiOjh9]

These reports are accompanied by an [Executive Summary->https://uic.org/IMG/pdf/sdb_report_2024_public.pdf], which highlights key insights and provides an analytical overview.

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc4148> 
  </div>
</div>

To access previous editions of the UIC Safety Public Report (up to 2024) free of charge, visit the [e-shop->https://shop.uic.org/en/].

The Confidential Report is exclusively available to contributors via a dedicated [members’ area->https://safetydb-apps.uic.org/Account/Login.aspx].

{{{Related Task Forces}}}

Since 2022, the UIC Task Force on Safety Barriers has been developing a definition and classification system for safety barriers, aiming to create a comprehensive global framework that provides an organized safety barrier library to enhance safety and interoperability across networks worldwide.

The task force laid a strong foundation for the principles of safety barrier definition and classification by publishing two white papers. 


{{Common safety barrier definitions to improve safety and interoperability}}

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc4357> 
  </div>
</div>

----

{{Classification of safety barriers to improve safety and interoperability}}

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc4198> 
  </div>
</div>

{{{UIC Contact}}}

Safety Database Manager: [Iryna Polzikova->mailto:polzikova@uic.org]
]]>
            </texte>
            <group1>Safety;</group1>
	    <themes>13;</themes>
          				<images>
					
				</images>
				<portfolio>
					doc4148;doc4198;doc4357;
				</portfolio>
        </rubrique>
        

        <rubrique xml:id="8">
		            <id>rub8</id>
            <parentid>rub0</parentid>
            <auteurs></auteurs>
            <logo></logo>
            <logourl>IMG/rubon145.jpg?1727099050</logourl>
            <titre>Special groups</titre>
	    <soustitre></soustitre>
            <pub>2024-06-18 13:43:28</pub>
            <desc>
                <![CDATA[]]>
            </desc>
            <texte>
                <![CDATA[]]>
            </texte>
            <group1></group1>
	    <themes></themes>
          				<images>
					
				</images>
				<portfolio>
					
				</portfolio>
        </rubrique>
        

        <rubrique xml:id="9">
		            <id>rub9</id>
            <parentid>rub8</parentid>
            <auteurs></auteurs>
            <logo></logo>
            <logourl>IMG/rubon145.jpg?1727099050</logourl>
            <titre>UIMC</titre>
	    <soustitre></soustitre>
            <pub>2024-06-18 13:43:28</pub>
            <desc>
                <![CDATA[]]>
            </desc>
            <texte>
                <![CDATA[<div class="row">
<div class="col-md-8">
The UIMC, the International Union of Railway Medical Services, is an autonomous special group under the aegis of the UIC, the International union of railways with headquarters in Paris.
</div>
<div class="col-md-4">
<img4023|left>
</div>
</div>

{{{Annual Congress}}}

The UIC Special Group of Railway Medical Directors (UIMC) holds annual congresses that address current topics in railway medicine. These congresses feature engaging workplace visits in the transport sector, work on adapting fitness standards for rail work within the UIMC medical guidelines, and include voting on updated internal regulations. They also provide ample networking opportunities. Medical directors and health representatives from railway and transport entities worldwide are welcome to attend. The congress is free for members of the UIMC and costs 600 euros per person for guests. Membership of UIMC is 1200 euros per annum and allows up to 4 participants to attend the annual congress.
 
The contact person for joining UIMC, or attending the congress as a guest, is the Secretary General of UIMC: 

Dr Stuart Turnbull, [Stuart.Turnbull@sonichealthplus.com.au->Stuart.Turnbull@sonichealthplus.com.au]
 or the President of UIMC: Dr Armand Casolin, [armand.casolin@transport.nsw.gov.au->armand.casolin@transport.nsw.gov.au]



{{{Tasks}}}

The UIMC performs the following tasks:

-* Promotion and dissemination of progress in relation to railway medicine
-* Facilitation of professional contact between railway medical officers with the aim of exchanging information and medical knowledge
-* Communication of research papers on railway medicine, regular inter-disciplinary and international exchange of medical knowledge at the annual scientific congress
-* Promotion of medical research specific to the railways and application of the results in day-to-day practice
-* Attainment of the highest possible level of railway operating safety and the best possible care of railway staff.


{{{History}}}

The UIMC was founded in 1948 as a company under Belgian law by a group of leading medical officers from European railway undertakings. It rapidly became a worldwide organisation with membership extending to Asia, Africa and South America. For organisational and structural reasons the UIMC has operated since 1995 under the aegis of the UIC as an autonomous special group of medical experts appointed by their railways as delegates of their medical services.

{{{Objectives}}}

The aim of UIMC members, like all those employed on the railways and external medical bodies working for railway companies, is to ensure and to improve the safety, functioning and efficiency of the railways. From a medical perspective, this is achieved by striving to attain healthy organisations with healthy workers, and by having medical standards that are evidence-based and best practice. This requires occupational health specialists who are well-acquainted with the working conditions and stresses and strains involved in the railway industry. Railway medical officers ensure that health and safety standards at work are adhered to and ensure that healthcare, psychological, preventive occupational medicine, and health promotion services are provided. Concerning globalisation and worldwide exchange of knowledge, advantage should be taken of synergies and international collaboration must be fostered.

{{{Activities}}}

The annual UIMC Congress provides a platform for the international exchange of experience, updates on advances in railway medicine through the presentation of scientific papers, the development of projects and the creation of working groups. In Europe, UIMC collaborates closely with the Community of European Railways (CER) with a view to harmonising provisions relating to medical fitness in cross-border traffic for interoperability purposes.

UIMC’s working groups deal with various scientific topics. In 2018-2019, two UIMC working groups focused on updating the chapters on alcohol and drugs and on psychiatric disorders in the UIMC Railway Medical Guidelines. Today, the impact of psychiatric disorders on wellbeing and the importance of mental health is being increasingly recognised in the railway industry and in society generally. Many medical issues in the railways are related to psychiatric disorders, including the misuse of drugs and alcohol, but international standards for assessment were hitherto outdated. For example, psychotropic medications are an important part of the effective treatment for most psychiatric disorders and, taken correctly, the benefits usually outweigh the side effects. Fitness for train driving and safety-critical work must be assessed in an internationally harmonised and scientifically robust way.

In September 2018 at the annual UIMC Congress in Luxembourg, numerous topics were discussed including health promotion, prevention programs, health surveillance, safety, drug usage compared to aptitude testing of performance, medical fitness assessment and new challenges relating to work methods and procedures. These discussions were continued in Rome in October 2019.

One of the goals of our organisation is to promote a continuous flow of information, thus enabling the ongoing growth in expertise of our members. Hence, in addition to the annual congress the UIMC encourages collaboration throughout the year via working groups, email and teleconference. 

Human factors are essential aspects of railway safety systems and common safety methods. We need an international exchange of knowledge and common standards to be able to advise the railways (both companies and national and international regulatory bodies) on standards for aptitude assessment and methods of promoting health amongst railway workers.

At the general assembly in Rome in 2019, a new management committee was elected which will set the strategic direction for UIMC for the coming years.

{{{UIMC congress}}}

{{Upcoming event}}
The UIC special group of railway medical directors (UIMC) will hold its annual congress from [8-10 October 2025 in Dublin, Ireland->https://uic.org/events/uimc-congress-2025]. The congress will cover current topics of railway medicine, offer interesting workplace visits in transport, work on adapting standards of fitness for rail work within the UIMC medical guidelines, vote on updated internal regulations and provide plenty of networking opportunities. Medical directors and health representatives of entities working for railways and transport around the world are welcome. The congress is free for members of the UIMC and costs 600 euros per person for guests. Membership of UIMC is 1200 euros per annum and allows up to 4 participants to attend the annual congress.
 
The contact person for joining UIMC, or attending the congress as a guest, is the Secretary General of UIMC: 
Dr Stuart Turnbull, [Stuart.Turnbull@sonichealthplus.com.au->Stuart.Turnbull@sonichealthplus.com.au]
 or the President of UIMC: Dr Armand Casolin, [armand.casolin@transport.nsw.gov.au->armand.casolin@transport.nsw.gov.au].

{{Previous events}}
Budapest (2024)
Frankfurt (2023)
Miami (2022)
Dublin (2021)
Rome (2019)
Luxembourg (2018)

{{{Invitation to participate}}}

The UIMC, therefore, invites all UIC member railways whose medical services are not yet represented on the UIMC, to cooperate within or with the UIMC. All forms of membership including railway company observer status or membership through their umbrella organisations from all continents are welcome. The UIC contact in Paris is:  [Frédéric Hénon.->mailto:henon@uic.org]

New membership enquiries should be directed to the Chair or the General Secretary of the UIMC.

{{{UIMC Railway Medical Guidelines}}}

<doc3126>
<doc3127>
<doc3128>
<doc3129>

{{{Contact}}}

If you wish to obtain a document or to leave a message contact:
-* The Vice Chair: [Alexandra Gertraud Hedenetz->mailto:g.hedenetz@ibg.at]
-* Or the General Secretary: [Stuart Turnbull->mailto:Stuart.Turnbull@sonichealthplus.com.au]
-* Or UIC contact in Paris: [Virginie Papillault->mailto:PAPILLAULT@uic.org]

please, provide your contact details.]]>
            </texte>
            <group1>UIMC Medical;</group1>
	    <themes>12;</themes>
          				<images>
					doc750;doc4023;
				</images>
				<portfolio>
					doc2982;doc3126;doc3127;doc3128;doc3129;
				</portfolio>
        </rubrique>
        

        <rubrique xml:id="12">
		            <id>rub12</id>
            <parentid>rub5</parentid>
            <auteurs></auteurs>
            <logo></logo>
            <logourl>IMG/rubon145.jpg?1727099050</logourl>
            <titre>Statistics</titre>
	    <soustitre></soustitre>
            <pub>2025-07-03 08:50:02</pub>
            <desc>
                <![CDATA[]]>
            </desc>
            <texte>
                <![CDATA[{{{RAILISA}}}

<div class="row">
<div class="col-2"></div>
<div class="col-8">[<img2690>->https://uic-stats.uic.org/]</div>
<div class="col-2"></div>
</div>

----

{{RAILISA}} ({{RAIL}} {{I}}nformation {{S}}ystem and {{A}}nalyses)}} is an online tool allowing users to visualise and download data provided by railway companies worldwide. Numerous indicators are available for more than 100 railway companies: length of lines and tracks on the infrastructure network, passenger and freight traffic (e.g. passenger-kilometres and tonne-kilometres), train movements, rolling stock, staff numbers, financial results, etc. Some of these indicators have been documented since 1995, and the database is updated frequently.

<div class="row">
<div class="col-xl-8">Visit RAILISA:</div>
<div class="col-xl-4"><a class="btn btn-block btn-outline-primary mb-3" role="button" href="http://uic-stats.uic.org">https://uic-stats.uic.org</a></div>
</div>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-xl-8">For further information, please consult the online user guide below or send an email to: stat@uic.org</div>
<div class="col-xl-4"><a class="btn btn-block btn-outline-info mb-3" role="button" href="https://uic-stats.uic.org//help_guide_A/"><i class="glyphicon glyphicon-info-sign"></i> RAILISA Guide (PDF)</a></div>
</div>

{{{Statistics Platform}}}

<h4>Tasks</h4>

-* {{Updating statistical indicators:}}
Indicators evolve in line with developments within member companies. Changes to the structure of the railway business, in particular, have had a major impact on railway statistics. The specific business sectors covered by new members, especially newcomers, must also be taken into account. Users’ needs are changing as new topics emerge, such as environment and quality. The role of the Statistics Platform is to define new indicators and data collection.

-* {{Harmonisation of statistics concepts:}}
This is one of the main tasks: if the concepts used are not harmonised, the data is not homogeneous and, as a result, any data analysis is distorted. Members vary greatly both in terms of legal status and areas of activity. It is increasingly difficult to make comparisons between companies (and groups) with companies being bought, made into subsidiaries or privatised. The coherence of railway statistics is at stake.

-* {{Cooperation:}}
The Statistics Platform is a discussion forum for statistics experts. It offers a means of strengthening personal ties, thereby improving the quality of data provision and exchange.

-* {{Unified Response:}}
By dint of its work and discussions, the Statistics Platform enables railway companies to speak with one voice when responding to the expectations and/or demands of international bodies. For instance, thanks to the efforts of the Statistics Platform, the new European regulation on railway statistics (91/2003) draws heavily on statistics collected by UIC with a view to avoiding duplication of work by the companies involved.

<h4>Organisation</h4>

The Statistics Platform comprises all those in charge of statistics at UIC member companies. Other UIC members may also participate at their request.

The participating members are mandated by their employers and undertake to actively contribute to the work of the platform and to international cooperation regarding the provision and exchange of statistical information as defined by the platform.

The Steering Committee is composed of a number of members of the platform, along with the chairman and the UIC statistics experts involved in the different statistics working groups. The Steering Committee prepares and develops the tasks to be carried out at the behest of the Platform or on its own initiative in order to ensure appropriate follow-up on statistics activities, a domain in which there is continuous demand. The Steering Commiteee meets for two days, three times a year.

The Statistics Platform holds a Plenary Meeting in December each year. 

The Chairman of the Statistics Group is Roman Štěrba of SŽCŽ.

{{{UIC statistical indicators}}}
<div class="row">
<div class="col-md-6">
<doc2789>
</div>
<div class="col-md-6">
<doc2790>
</div>
</div>
<div class="row">
<div class="col-md-6">
<doc2788>
</div>
</div>

{{{Passenger and freight traffic trends}}}
-* [Traffic trends among UIC member companies in the first half of 2024->https://uic.org/com/enews/article/traffic-trends-among-uic-member-companies-in-the-first-half-of-2024#:~:text=In%20the%20first%20half%20of%202024%2C%20rail%20passenger%20volumes%20increased,levels%20for%20the%20first%20time]
-* [Traffic trends among UIC member companies in 2023->https://uic.org/com/enews/article/traffic-trends-among-uic-member-companies-in-2023]
-* [Traffic trends among UIC member companies in the first half of 2023->https://uic.org/com/enews/article/traffic-trends-among-uic-member-companies-in-the-first-half-of-2023]
-* [Traffic trends among UIC member companies in 2022->https://uic.org/com/enews/article/traffic-trends-among-uic-member-companies-in-2022]
-* [Traffic trends among UIC member companies in the first half of 2022->https://uic.org/com/enews/article/traffic-trends-among-uic-member-companies-in-the-first-half-of-2022-11291]
-* [Traffic trends among UIC member companies in 2021->https://uic.org/com/enews/article/traffic-trends-among-uic-member-companies-in-2021]
-* [Traffic trends among UIC member companies in the first half of 2021->https://uic.org/com/enews/article/traffic-trends-among-uic-member-companies-in-the-first-half-of-2021]
-* [Rail traffic trends in 2020 among UIC member companies->https://www.uic.org/com/enews/article/rail-traffic-trends-in-2020-among-uic-member-companies]
-* [Traffic trends in the first half of 2020 for member railways in the UIC Europe region->https://www.uic.org/com/enews/article/traffic-trends-in-the-first-half-of-2020-for-member-railways-in-the-uic-europe]
-* [Rail traffic trends 2019 for railway members in the UIC Europe region->https://uic.org/com/enews/nr/693/article/rail-traffic-trends-2019-for-railway-members-in-the-uic-europe-region]

{{{Rail transport in the world}}}
<div class="row">
<div class="col-md-6">
<doc2791>
</div>
<div class="col-md-6">
<doc2795>
</div>
</div>

<div class="row">
<div class="col-md-6">
<doc2792>
</div>
<div class="col-md-6">
<doc2793>
</div>
</div>

<div class="row">
<div class="col-md-6">
<doc2794>
</div>
</div>



{{{UIC Contact}}}
For any further information please contact [{{Railway Statistics Group}}.->mailto:stat@uic.org]  
]]>
            </texte>
            <group1>Statistics;</group1>
	    <themes>23;</themes>
          				<images>
					doc2690;
				</images>
				<portfolio>
					doc2788;doc2789;doc2790;doc2791;doc2792;doc2793;doc2794;doc2795;
				</portfolio>
        </rubrique>
        

        <rubrique xml:id="13">
		            <id>rub13</id>
            <parentid>rub0</parentid>
            <auteurs></auteurs>
            <logo></logo>
            <logourl>IMG/rubon145.jpg?1727099050</logourl>
            <titre>Passenger</titre>
	    <soustitre></soustitre>
            <pub>2025-08-05 13:52:57</pub>
            <desc>
                <![CDATA[Cooperation and best-practice exchange are important drivers for the promotion of passenger rail as the "green" and customer-friendly mode of transport for the future.]]>
            </desc>
            <texte>
                <![CDATA[<div class="highlight">
Passenger railway accounts for 50% of rail activity, 8% of global passenger transport and less than 2% of greenhouse gas emissions from passenger transport, and is believed to be the backbone of future mobility.
</div>


{{{General context of the business activity}}}
With the emergence of new technologies, changes in customer behaviour and choices regarding mobility, and the development of competition in the rail sector, railway undertakings and infrastructure managers are shifting towards a more customercentred approach when providing services, investing in innovation and research to offer more personalised and seamless journeys.

Against this background, the UIC Passenger Department acts as a lever to transform the railway business by offering sectoral technical solutions (IRS), opportunities for knowledge exchange, networking platforms and tools, and support for the whole rail sector: railway undertakings and infrastructure managers, but also decision makers, research centres, universities or Ticket Vendors, for all aspects related to rail passenger transport.

{{{Reference to how the business is organised}}}
UIC’s passenger activity is inspired by the involvement of its members in the Passenger Global Forum, led by Manel Villalante I Llauradó (Renfe).The forum is subdivided into five areas of activity:

-* [{{Passenger Services Group (PSG)}}->rubrique56]
-* [{{Intercity and High-Speed Committee}}->rubrique21] 
-* [{{Commuter and Regional Train Services (CRTS)}}->rubrique54]
-* [{{Stations Managers Global Group}}->rubrique55] 
-* [{{Tourism opportunities for Railways}}->rubrique91] 

And a special group:
-* [{{RIC/A}}->rubrique71] (Agreements on the exchange and use of passenger cars and self-propelled units in international rail traffic)

{{{Global Passenger Forum}}}
The UIC Global Passenger Forum was set up so that members all over the world could jointly adopt a global approach to UIC Passenger activity, encompassing the five passenger sectors (Intercity and High-Speed, Commuter and Regional Trains, Stations, Passenger Services Group and TopRail) and relevant projects, and discuss and set common priorities, strategies and directives, eventually to be coordinated with other forums and platforms where appropriate.

The purpose of the UIC Global Passenger Forum is to:
-* Set out a global and strategic vision for UIC Passenger activities, and establish guidelines and priority lines of work;
-* Transversely coordinate and supervise Passenger-related work conducted by the five groups and committees;
-* Collect results and deliverables from the different activities and projects undertaken, with a view to disseminating outcomes as widely as possible among members, within the scope of the applicable intellectual property rights;
-* Select and endorse candidates put forward for the positions of chair or other roles within the groups and committees, to be ratified by the UIC General Assembly in accordance with UIC Statutes;
-* Coordinate with the Railway System Forum and other platforms, such as [Digitalisation->rubrique88], [Standardisation->rubrique48], [RICG (Research and Innovation Coordination Group)->rubrique31], [Safety->rubrique42], etc., on key issues relating to Passenger activity;
-* Promote and facilitate meetings with other organisations relevant to passenger transport, such as [UITP (International Union of Public Transport)->https://www.uitp.org/], [CIT (International Rail Transport Committee)->https://www.cit-rail.org/], [OSJD (Organisation for Cooperation of Railways)->https://en.osjd.org/], [CER (Community of European Railway and Infrastructure Companies)->https://www.cer.be/], [RNE (RailNetEurope)->https://rne.eu/], [Association of American Railroads (AAR)->https://www.aar.org/], etc.
-* Integrate and coordinate, in a coherent and consistent way, activities and projects relating to passenger transport developed at the regional level of UIC. Recommend that the General Assembly approve cross-regional projects and activities adopted by the various groups and committees under the Passenger Global Forum.

{{{High-Level Passenger Meeting}}}

The High-Level Passenger Meeting (HLPM), co-organised by UIC and CER, is an event
aimed at European Passenger CEOs to discuss strategic topics relating to the challenges faced by the European railways.

This meeting brings top managers from Passenger railway companies across Europe together for discussions on important rail passenger transport policy issues.
The purpose of this meeting is to review key questions about European railway passenger policy, and to address the technical and political challenges facing passenger transport in the future.

During the last HLPM on 2 October 2020, the focus was on the development of the OSDM (Open Sales and Distribution Model), as per the resolution from the previous HLPM. One standard had been developed, comprising two parts: OSDM Platform and OSDM Online. Other topics were also discussed, such as support for companies during the Covid-19 pandemic, the start of the International Rail Passenger Platform, and the opportunities for flight substitution via rail in Europe.

The next HLPM will be held on 8 October 2021 in Paris, and Passenger CEOs will discuss strategic subjects, including distribution, the ‘New Normal’ and new services.]]>
            </texte>
            <group1>Passenger;</group1>
	    <themes>18;</themes>
          				<images>
					
				</images>
				<portfolio>
					doc2605;doc3596;
				</portfolio>
        </rubrique>
        

        <rubrique xml:id="21">
		            <id>rub21</id>
            <parentid>rub13</parentid>
            <auteurs></auteurs>
            <logo></logo>
            <logourl>IMG/rubon145.jpg?1727099050</logourl>
            <titre>Intercity and High-Speed </titre>
	    <soustitre></soustitre>
            <pub>2019-02-07 17:43:20</pub>
            <desc>
                <![CDATA[]]>
            </desc>
            <texte>
                <![CDATA[{{{High-Speed rail}}}

{{A comprehensive system allowing door-to-door transportation}}
Growing environmental awareness due to the pandemic has resulted in a shift in customer mobility habits and has revived demand for low-carbon transport alternatives such as long-distance rail travel. With more passengers choosing to travel sustainably, HSR (High-Speed Rail) is often described as the transport mode of the future for many reasons. High-speed trains also play a key role in achieving regional integration and helping to create socio-economically balanced societies at global level. 

The current evolutionary trend of the world HSR network shows a very sharp increase in the length of the network in Asian countries. Development and implementation of highspeed lines are being studied in all regions worldwide. 

End-to-end transportation is a must and intermodal service complementarity is also one of the factors in the operational and financial success of HSR. 
<span style="position: absolute;left: -43123px;">The best casinos in Canada - <a href = "https://slots-online-canada.ca/">https://slots-online-canada.ca/</a> vary depending on personal preferences, but some of the top online casinos include Jackpot City, Spin Casino!</span>
High-speed rail combines many different elements which constitute a “whole, integrated system”: an infrastructure for new lines designed for speeds of 250 km/h and above; upgraded existing lines for speeds of up to 200 or even 220 km/h, including interconnecting lines between high-speed sections; its rolling stock, especially designed specifically for train sets; telecommunications, signalling, operating conditions and equipment, etc. Technology is expected to have a major influence on infrastructure development over the next 20 years. 

Since many high-speed trains are also compatible with the conventional network, the term “high-speed traffic” is also frequently used for the movements of such trains on conventional lines but at speeds lower than those allowed on high-speed infrastructure. <span style="position: absolute;left: -43123px;"><a href = "https://abcoemstore.com/product/adobe-acrobat-pro-dc-2017/">Download the Acrobat Pro 2017</a> or Standard 2017 installer from below. You need the serial number to complete the installation.</span>

Over three billion passengers travel on highspeed trains each year. High-speed rail is continuing to develop around the world; there are now almost 56,000 km of lines in operation worldwide. In 30 years, this figure will have at least doubled. 

Given the stronger demand for low-carbon transport alternatives such as long-distance rail travel, railway undertakings are launching, developing, or reviving night train services, with the aim of establishing new connections and enlarging the current night train network. This includes developing attractive services to meet the growing demands from passengers such as competitive travel times, comfort, good connectivity (thus fostering regional development between smaller cities and rural areas) as well as being more climate friendly.

{{For further information about high-speed rail history, please visit:}} 
<div class="col-xl-6"><a class="btn btn-block btn-outline-primary mb-3" role="button" href="article103">High-Speed Rail History</a></div>

{{{Intercity and High-Speed Committee}}}

The Intercity and High-Speed Committee brings together several UIC railway members who are either active in long distance or high-speed rail domains in their day-to-day operations or have identified it as a development objective. 

Committee plenary meetings and onsite technical visits provide opportunities to exchange best practice and discuss common problems. The ICHSC therefore greatly benefits attendees, offering the chance to identify solutions to common issues, compare approaches, or develop a global vision. 

Studies are also conducted within the framework of the Committee to deepen understanding of particular subjects specific to long-distance and high-speed fields. 

The Committee offers a wealth of expertise to members through discussions, communication, studies and projects. 

UIC makes this expertise available in several ways: by means of the high-speed database and maps, and by issuing reference documents and numerous publications.

{{Presentation of the UIC Intercity and High-speed committee}}

<div class="embed-responsive embed-responsive-16by9">
     <iframe src="//www.youtube.com/embed/0P0HQfea3bo" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


 
{{{Statistics – database and high-speed world}}}
Each year UIC produces an atlas providing an overview of high-speed lines in the world: those in commercial operation, under construction, currently under development, and planned in the medium or long term. 

The UIC High-Speed Rail Atlas is a unique document that provides very detailed information about all high-speed lines around the world, supplied and reviewed by UIC members.
{{For further information, please visit:}} 
<div class="col-xl-6"><a class="btn btn-block btn-outline-primary mb-3" role="button" href="article178">High-Speed Databases and Atlas</a></div>

{{{Alliance of Universities for High-Speed Rail}}}
The UIC Alliance of Universities was established in 2015 under the aegis of UIC for the development of High-Speed Rail (HSR).

The Alliance is a global academic network including universities, institutes of technology, polytechnics, engineering, architecture and business schools that have shown substantial involvement in the development of high-speed railways.

{{For further information, please visit:}} 
<div class="col-xl-6"><a class="btn btn-block btn-outline-primary mb-3" role="button" href="article410">High-Speed Alliance of Universities </a></div>

{{{High-Speed Rail Projects}}}
{{Research and publications}}
ICHSC members may also decide to work jointly on specific High-Speed Rail (HSR) studies. Recent projects under finalisation include: 
-* A benchmark study aimed at anticipating the impact of autonomous road vehicles
-* A study for a better understanding of travel cost evolution, looking at HSR marginal cost and value of time 
-* An innovative tool for decision-makers to understand and evaluate the operational efficiency of HSR, whether existing or planned 
-* A benchmark study on customer experience based on specific methods and tools for CX assessment 

Several other projects, covering cooperation between air and HS rail, artificial intelligence applied to HS, and the ‘New Normal’ post Covid pandemic, are underway.

<div class="col-xl-6"><a class="btn btn-block btn-outline-primary mb-3" role="button" href="article179">Publications </a></div>

{{Training on High-Speed Systems - Level I and Level II (THSS)}}
UIC members send employees to seminars organised by UIC for training on high-speed. The content is based on the state of the art and is delivered by recognised experts in the field, with two levels. 

THSS Level I consists of a series of theoretical sessions and technical visits. 

THSS Level II is more in-depth and makes use of the special tools developed by FFE. 
Bespoke sessions can be proposed for groups of sufficient size at the request of UIC members.

{{{UIC World Congress on High-Speed Rail}}}
The UIC World Congress on High-Speed Rail offers direct access to people and ideas, all gathered in a single location. It is globally renowned as the most prominent and large-scale global event on high-speed rail.

Organised every two years, this Congress addresses strategic issues linked to the national and international development of high-speed rail systems.

The 11th UIC World Congress on High-Speed Rail will be held in Morocco in the first half of 2023.

The UIC HIGHSPEED 2023, is a unique event mobilising policy makers, authorities, railway companies, suppliers, customers, research institutes, universities, etc. around the slogan “High-speed rail, the right speed for our planet”.

The Congress is organised around three main blocks: sessions, an exhibition and technical visits. 

<a class="btn btn-block btn-primary" href="https://uichighspeed.org/">World Congress on High–Speed Rail:
https://uichighspeed.org
</a>

{{{International Railway Solutions – IRSs for high-speed rail}}}
Technical harmonisation of the railway system has been a core objective of UIC, acting as an SSO (standards setting organisation), since its creation in 1922. Its members – the operators of the world’s railways – have, over the years, developed the “UIC Code”, comprising UIC leaflets, which define the common rules that apply to ensure safety and efficiency in the design, construction, operation and maintenance of the railway system. A significant number of these deliverables are used outside the railway operating community. UIC now produces IRSs, produced through collaboration and consensus, to meet the business needs of the railway operating community (ROC). The IRSs set out harmonised operational requirements, generic methodologies and assessment criteria for the efficient design, construction, operation and maintenance of rail systems. 

The IRSs for high-speed rail are a subset of the overall series of IRSs and come under the remit of the Intercity & High-Speed Committee.
The IRS HS working group meets regularly to produce new IRSs or to update/migrate UIC leaflets to become IRSs.

{{IRS 60661:}} Railway application – HighSpeed – Dynamic integration tests and trial operation before revenue operation review, published in October 2020: <div class="col-xl-4"><a class="btn btn-block btn-outline-info mb-3" role="button" href="https://shop.uic.org/en/railway-application-high-speed-dynamic-integration-tests-and-trial-operation-before-revenue-operation"></i>IRS 60661</a></div>
{{IRS 60680:}} Design of a High-Speed Railway – Infrastructure: launched for production in December 2020. 
{{IRS 6068:}} Design of a High-Speed Railway – Signalling and Communication: launched for production in December 2020. 
{{IRS 60682:}} Design of a High-Speed Railway – Energy: Draft 4.1, 7th edition, endorsed by GPF in April 2021. 
{{IRS 60683:}} Design of a High-Speed Railway – Interfaces: approval is planned in first quarter 2022. 
{{IRS 60660:}} Compatibility of High-Speed trains: started in 2021. 
{{IRS 70734:}} Adaptation of safety installations to High-Speed: started in 2021.



{{{Night Trains Working Group}}}
During the June 2021 plenary session of the UIC Intercity and High-Speed Committee, the ICHSC members decided on the creation of a Night Train Working Group Committee with the aim to meet the growing demands from passengers such as competitive travel times, comfort, good connectivity as well as being more climate friendly. 

The aim is for night trains to play an important role in the post-pandemic world and significantly contribute to reduce transport emissions. In Europe, given the vision for 2030 of a network with 15 domestic overnight lines, the challenge for the working group is to work as a team and capture this market of approximately 10 million passengers per year, mostly shifted from planes and cars, also representing an important saving of CO<sub>2</sub>. 

The main goals of this UIC Night Train Working Group are to: 
-* Build a partnership bringing together the night trains players 
-* Implement standards for coaches and sales systems 
-* Strengthen the economic situation of night trains 
-* Specify path fees/track access charges for night trains 

In addition, the creation of this Working Group is an opportunity to share best practice and develop common projects and standards in the areas of rolling stock, operations, corridors, cross-border, business and economic models, and on-board services.

{{High-speed }}

]]>
            </texte>
            <group1>High-speed;</group1>
	    <themes>8;</themes>
          				<images>
					doc3623;
				</images>
				<portfolio>
					doc2685;doc3456;doc3829;
				</portfolio>
        </rubrique>
        

        <rubrique xml:id="22">
		            <id>rub22</id>
            <parentid>rub0</parentid>
            <auteurs></auteurs>
            <logo></logo>
            <logourl>IMG/rubon145.jpg?1727099050</logourl>
            <titre>Sustainability</titre>
	    <soustitre></soustitre>
            <pub>2025-03-11 12:52:27</pub>
            <desc>
                <![CDATA[Making railway greener, quieter and more energy efficient.]]>
            </desc>
            <texte>
                <![CDATA[<div class="highlight">
Sustainable development is considered one of the main global challenges facing the world today and is an important aspect of transport development. UIC and its members work continuously to demonstrate how rail can be part of the solution to the challenge of sustainable development.
</div>

<div class="col-md-5 float-right bg-secondary text-white px-4 ml-3 mb-3">

{{{Key Publications}}}
-* [The sustainable mobility that we want->https://shop.uic.org/en/other-documents/14384-the-sustainable-mobility-that-we-want.html] - 2022
-* [Rail On Track->https://www.iea.org/reports/rail] - IEA rail tracking report, June 2020
-* [The Future of Rail, Opportunities for energy and the environment->https://shop.uic.org/en/other-documents/9438-the-future-of-rail.html], by International Energy Agency (IEA) in collaboration with UIC, 2019 
-* [UIC and IEA Railway Handbook->article200]
-* [Transport Climate Action Pathway->https://unfccc.int/climate-action/marrakech-partnership/reporting-tracking/pathways/transport-climate-action-pathway], UNFCCC 2021
-* [The Slocat Transport and Global Transport Status Report (2nd Edition)->https://tcc-gsr.com/] 


</div>


{{{The backbone of future sustainable transport system}}}

{{Railway has a central role to play in decarbonising transport.}}


As the cleanest and greenest high-volume transport, rail has an essential role in creating sustainable lifestyles and economies.  While representing 8% of global passenger and freight transport activity (in passenger km/tonne km), railway represents only 2% of the transport sector emissions. Global Green House gas emissions from transport are continuing to rise, accounting for 14% of all emissions in 2018. Rail is bucking this trend and has been the only mode to actually reduce its emissions, down by 2% between 2000 and 2018.  Transport demand is expected to double in the same time we have to decarbonise, before 2050.  It is clear that today’s challenges can only be met with rail as the backbone of a seamlessly connected sustainable mobility system.  Rail is a central pillar to transformative climate action in transport. It is the fastest and most cost-efficient way to decarbonise people’s daily mobility and logistics chains.  Unleashing the full benefits of rail for decarbonisation, will be key to significantly cutting emissions from the transport sector in line with the Paris Agreement.  

{{Rail networks are frugal by design:}}
-* Frugality in energy consumption: whether in terms of energy per capita or globally, railways and public transport are extremely efficient: passenger rail transport requires less than 1/10th of the energy needed to move an individual by car or by aeroplane;
-* Frugality in public space: whether in urban or rural areas, the occupation of public space is minimal, and the promotion of rail transport will once again give citizens the possibility of enjoying more public space with better air and soil quality with a greater level of safety;
-* Frugality in terms of life cycle: the lifetime of railways can be up to 50 years, minimising the need to reinvest regularly in non-renewable resources.

Climate change is not the only global sustainability issue that rail can help solve. The railway sector indeed plays an important societal role in relation with the ecosystem and biodiversity, both in urban and rural areas.

By 2050, railway infrastructure should be an integral part of the natural landscape and therefore should become a “green network” connecting biotopes, enabling species migration and providing diverse habitats for many different species. UIC is working on other key issues, such as the promotion of the sustainable use of resources (ballast, concrete, steel, water etc.), the reduction of external costs by means of careful monitoring and controlling methods of noise and vibration, sustainable land use, and of airborne particulate matter, in order to help the railways to contribute to the achievement of the United Nations Sustainable Development Goals.


{{{The UIC Sustainability Platform}}}
Our vision:
<quote>A railway that supports a green recovery as the backbone of sustainable mobility.   Connectivity that contributes to healthy and sustainable lifestyles and economies on every continent – that is zero emissions, a community hub, accessible for all, and is both biodiverse and a good neighbour.</quote>

UIC and its members work together to shine a light on how rail can be part of the solution to the challenge of sustainable development as well as find solutions to make our railways even cleaner, greener and quieter. The Sustainability Platform focuses on 5 main environmental sustainability topics.

{{Our Sectors:}}
-* [{{Air Quality}}->rubrique127]
-* [{{Circular Economy}}->rubrique112]
-* [{{Energy and CO<sub>2</sub>}}->rubrique25]
-* [{{Noise and Vibration}}->rubrique24]
-* [{{Sustainable Land Use}}->rubrique113]

The UIC Sustainability Platform, meet in plenary twice a year and is currently chaired by Christine Vannoppen (LINEAS). The platform works with a steering committee to provide direction. To get involved contact  [{{Sustainability Unit}}.->mailto:sustainability@uic.org]  

The sustainability platform connects with other UIC departments such as the Freight, Passenger and Rail System departments on the above and other sustainability topics including Sustainable Procurement, sustainable finance, inclusive stations, alternative fuels, and climate change adaptation. 

{{{Key activities}}} 
-* Representing the railway sector internationally and advocating its sustainability at international events, including the UN Conference of Parties, in order to raise the profile of the railways on the international stage
-* Contributing railway content to publications for international sustainability groups and organisations in order to represent the interests of the global railway community
-* Collecting and reporting the environmental database and assessments for railways
-* Developing and updating international railway solutions (IRS)
-* Developing and hosting tools to support the mission of the platform including [{{Rail Sustainability Index}}->article847], [{{EcoPassenger}}->article75] and [{{Ecotransit}}->article185]
-* Responding quickly to rapid changes to the environment and being proactive in proposing projects to fight climate change, address resource depletion, loss of biodiversity, social inequality, and pollution

{{{The Global Rail Sustainability Taskforce}}}
New in 2021, a new taskforce formed as part of the platform, with member representation from all around the world.  For any further information please contact [{{Sustainability Unit}}.->mailto:sustainability@uic.org]  

{{The taskforce purpose is:}}
-* Being an inspirational leadership team representing all regions and diverse perspectives 
-* Uniting the rail industry on sustainability, with a customer focus and other important stakeholders
-* Confidently and enthusiastically championing the role of modal shift from aviation and private road vehicles to rail and connected sustainable forms of transport.   
-* Promoting sustainable connectivity and the role of rail in a just and green recovery from the COVID 19 pandemic that accelerates the path to a decarbonised economy
-* Providing strategic oversight and direction to the UIC on the topic of Sustainability
-* Focusing UIC activities on the key challenges of the members and the needs of rail customers 
-* Giving direction on both priority themes and high-level risks and opportunities – Long Term strategy to position rail as the backbone of sustainable mobility 
-* Creating a united vision with key messages and identifying the most important collective targets and actions

{{{The UIC Sustainability Unit}}}
The UIC Sustainability Unit is the support secretariate for the Sustainability Platform. We consider it our mission to help empower the global railway community to be a driving force in a greener future through collaborative knowledge and advocacy. 
For any further information please contact [{{Sustainability Unit}}.->mailto:sustainability@uic.org]  

{{{Global Rail Sustainability Report}}}
<doc3806>


]]>
            </texte>
            <group1>Sustainability;Environment;</group1>
	    <themes>19;20;</themes>
          				<images>
					
				</images>
				<portfolio>
					doc2602;doc3806;
				</portfolio>
        </rubrique>
        

        <rubrique xml:id="24">
		            <id>rub24</id>
            <parentid>rub22</parentid>
            <auteurs></auteurs>
            <logo></logo>
            <logourl>IMG/rubon145.jpg?1727099050</logourl>
            <titre>Noise and vibration</titre>
	    <soustitre></soustitre>
            <pub>2025-03-06 14:17:14</pub>
            <desc>
                <![CDATA[Noise working group, Vibration Working group, LOWNOISEPAD]]>
            </desc>
            <texte>
                <![CDATA[{{{UIC Noise and Vibration Sector}}}

Rail is the most sustainable mode of transport, consuming less energy, requiring less space, and emitting significantly less CO₂ than other transport modes. However, noise remains one of the key environmental challenges for railway stakeholders. 

For instance, rail is the second-largest noise pollutant in transport after roads, with noise pollution ranking second only to air pollution in environmental health impacts. Growing public concern and increasing regulatory pressure require the rail sector to continuously improve its environmental performance. 

While significant progress has been made, further efforts are essential to ensure railways remain both a competitive and environmentally responsible transport solution.

{{Our Role}}

The UIC Noise and Vibration Sector supports the railway community by facilitating knowledge transfer, coordinating research, and engaging with policymakers and stakeholders focusing on:
-* Collaboration & Knowledge Sharing – Providing a platform for members to exchange best practices and align on global sustainability goals.
-* Innovation & Solutions – Advancing noise reduction technologies, improving track maintenance, and integrating noise action plans into urban mobility strategies.
-* Policy & Regulation – Addressing EU and national requirements, guiding mitigation strategies, and advocating for cost-effective solutions.
-* Biannual sector meetings provide members with opportunities for collaboration, technical exchange, and strategic planning.

For further information about the UIC Noise and Vibration Sector: 
<iframe width="100%" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/sCjCaMrDapc?si=qCWBTWidI7zlfYzJ" title="YouTube video player" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" allowfullscreen></iframe>


{{{Noise Working Group }}}

{{Chaired by Jakob OERTLI, SBB}}

Noise is a critical environmental aspect of the railways. Noise issues must be addressed if rail traffic is to be promoted. In this sense, the noise working group aims to share knowledge on noise mitigation practices and supports the development of new noise reduction methodologies. The group also promotes the discussion of the relevant noise issues between the various stakeholders such as the EU Commission, national governments, railways, and lineside residents. To this extent, the group publishes regular state-of-the-art reports and organises workshops. Sector members engage in discussions and technical activities on selected topics covering various issues in the railway noise domain, including Curve Squeal Noise, Vehicle Noise, and Acoustic Rail Roughness.  


{{{Vibration Working Group}}}

{{Chaired by Alf EKBLAD, Trafikverket}}

Vibration issues are addressed in the sustainability platform as an environmental issue and its impact on human health. As a result of efforts to eliminate noise problems, there is a growing concern about ground-borne vibration and its effect on people living near the railways. Therefore, the main objective of the working group is to increase the sharing of information about vibration measurement, prediction and assessment methodologies and to share best practices. Group members focus on active problem-solving by organising meetings, workshops, and surveys, aiming to increase their knowledge and convey it to other stakeholders by publishing a state-of-the-art report on vibration.


{{{Projects}}}

{{Ongoing Projects  }} 

<img4268|left>
{{1. NOVITA – NOise and Vibration Technical Advice}}
(2021– Ongoing)

NOVITA aims to represent the global railway sector, serving as the project funding the Noise and Vibration sector. This ensures the development of technical activities and research, and publishing relevant reports.
More information is available on the [Project page->https://uic.org/projects-99/article/novita]

----

<img4269|left>
{{2. EU-RAIL QuieterRail }} 
(2024-2027)

QuieterRail aims to introduce a step change in predicting and mapping railway noise and vibration, in the acceptance testing of rolling stock, and in promoting cost-effective noise mitigation.

For more information have a look at our brochure [here->https://uic.sharepoint.com/sites/SD/Documents%20partages/Forms/AllItems.aspx?id=%2Fsites%2FSD%2FDocuments%20partages%2FSustainability%20Platform%2FNoise%20Vibration%2F4%2E%20Workshops%2F2025%2FA5%2DQuieter%2DRail%2Donline%2Epdf&parent=%2Fsites%2FSD%2FDocuments%20partages%2FSustainability%20Platform%2FNoise%20Vibration%2F4%2E%20Workshops%2F2025].

----
<img4270|left>
{{3. ACORD -ACOustics of Reprofiling and onboarRD monitoring of rail roughness}}
(2024-2027)

More information is available on the [Project page->https://uic.org/projects-99/article/acord].

----

{{Completed Projects}}


<img4268|left>
{{1. Noise Technical Advice}}
(2018-2021)

The project served as predecessor of the ongoing NOVITA Project, addressing railway noise on a global scale.

More information is available on the [Project page->https://uic.org/projects-99/article/noise-technical-advice].

---- 

<img4271|left>
{{2. LOWNOISEPAD - Low-cost noise control by optimised rail pad}}
(2021-2023)

The Low-Cost Noise Control by Optimised Rail Pad (LOWNOISEPAD) project aimed to evaluate the effectiveness of rail pads in reducing noise emissions during train pass-bys. The project included extensive measurements and analysis across multiple test sites and rolling stock types to assess the acoustic performance of different rail pads. Additionally, a software tool was developed to visualize and analyze the results, enabling users to estimate changes in noise emissions when rail pads are modified.

More information is available on the [Project page->https://uic.org/projects-99/article/lownoisepad].

----

<img4272|left>
{{3. RIVAS - Railway Induced Vibration Abatement Solutions}}
(2011-2013)
 
RIVAS is a collaborative rail research project conducted under the 7th Framework Programme for EU research (FP7) and comprising 26 partners from all over Europe.
The objective of the project is to find solutions to vibrations and vibration induced noise from rail traffic, which have a huge impact on people’s living and working conditions near railway lines. 

More information is available on the [Project page->https://uic.org/projects-99/article/rivas].

----

<img4273|left>
{{4. SILENCE Project}}
(2005-2008)

The Silence project focused on the development of noise reduction solutions for rail and road, more particularly for urban situations, applying a global approach, with work packages dealing with noise sources to be evaluated, and work packages on global modelling, noise annoyance and noise mapping.

----

<img4274|left>
{{5. STAIRRS - Strategies and Tools to Assess and Implement Noise Reducing Measures for Railway Systems}}
(2000-2003)

The STAIRRS proposal was submitted in response to the EU’s 5th Framework Programme “Sustainable Mobility and Intermodality: Competitive and Sustainable Growth” where the need was identified for a study to assess the relative effectiveness, benefits, and costs of several railway noise mitigation options applied to vehicles or track.

More information is available on the [Project page->https://uic.org/projects-99/article/stairrs].

----

{{{Publications}}}
{{Track noise measurement guidelines - A methodology to measure and compare noise emissions during train pass-bys}}

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
<div class><a class="btn btn-block btn-outline-info mb-3" role="button" href="https://shop.uic.org/en/1-laying-and-maintenance-of-track/14479-track-noise-measurement-guidelines-a-methodology-to-measure-and-compare-noise-emissions-during-train-pass-bys.html"></i>IRS 75717</a></div>
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<button class="btn btn-primary" type="button" data-toggle="collapse" data-target="#collapse1" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse1">Description</button>
<div class="collapse" id="collapse1">
  <div class="card card-body">

The International Union of Railways (UIC), through its Noise and Vibration Sector (NV), works with its members to better understand noise-generating mechanisms to make tangible progress towards being a better neighbour. The vision of the UIC NV Sector is to provide a global dialogue to integrate sustainability into railway operations and maintenance with a common goal of managing noise emissions better.

  </div>
</div>
 </div>
</div>
----
<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc3792> 
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">Nuisance and Health Impacts of Railway Noise - Noise and Vibration Technical Advice (NOVITÀ) Project</div>
<a href="https://uic.org/IMG/pdf/nuisance_and_health_impacts_of_railway_noise.pdf"class="btn btn-primary">Get your copy</a>

  </div>
  </div>

----
 
<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc3793> 
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">Noise from parked and stationary trains: An analysis of operational and technical solutions</div>
<a href="https://uic.org/IMG/pdf/noise_from_parked_and_stationary_trains.pdf"class="btn btn-primary">Get your copy</a>

  </div>
  </div>

----
<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc118> 
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">UIC Research Project: Managing Noise from Parked Trains - 2014</div>
<a href="https://uic.org/IMG/pdf/m111955_04_ber_3e_couv.pdf"class="btn btn-primary">Get your copy</a>

  </div>
  </div>

----

{{UIC Railway Noise in Europe}}

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc3329>
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">UIC Railway noise in Europe - State of the art report - 2021</div>
<a href="https://uic.org/IMG/pdf/railway_noise_in_europe_state_of_the_art_report.pdf"class="btn btn-primary">Get your copy</a>

  </div>
  </div>

----

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc1504>
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">UIC Railway noise in Europe - State of the art report - 2016</div>
<a href="https://uic.org/IMG/pdf/railway_noise_in_europe_2016_final.pdf"class="btn btn-primary">Get your copy</a>

  </div>
  </div>

----

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc3011> 
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">UIC Railway noise in Europe - State of the art report - 2010</div>
<a href="https://uic.org/IMG/pdf/uic_railway_noise_the_state_of_the_art_2010.pdf"class="btn btn-primary">Get your copy</a>

  </div>
  </div>

----

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc2996> 
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">UIC Network Noise and Vibration Flyer</div>
<a href="https://uic.org/IMG/pdf/uic_noise_flyer_2019.pdf"class="btn btn-primary">Download flyer</a>

  </div>
  </div>
----

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc2486> 
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">State of the Art Report - Railway Induced Vibration - 2017</div>
<a href="https://uic.org/IMG/pdf/uic-railway-induced-vibration-report-2017."class="btn btn-primary">Get your copy</a>

  </div>
  </div>
----

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc131> 
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">Railway Noise - Technical Measures Catalogue</div>
<div class="h5">July 2013</div>
<a href="https://shop.uic.org/en/other-reports/1263-railway-noise-technical-measures-catalogue.html" class="btn btn-primary">View brochure on shop.uic.org</a>
<button class="btn btn-primary" type="button" data-toggle="collapse" data-target="#collapse9" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse9">Description</button>
<div class="collapse" id="collapse9">
  <div class="card card-body">

There is a growing awareness of the impact of railway noise on public health, which has 
resulted in pressure from line-side inhabitants, governments and health organizations for increased noise mitigation. As a consequence, noise can be a limiting factor for many railway operations, introducing additional costs for mitigation, demands for limits on availability/capacity and resistance to expansion of the network. 

Recent years have seen the development of new, and refinement of existing, strategies and technologies for noise management. Railway companies often face calls to implement these, and demonstrate that progress has been made with the use of new and innovative technology. 

  </div>
</div>
  </div>
</div>

----

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc136> 
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">The real cost of railway noise mitigation - A risk assessment - 2013</div>

<button class="btn btn-primary" type="button" data-toggle="collapse" data-target="#collapse10" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse10">Description</button>
<div class="collapse" id="collapse10">
  <div class="card card-body">

The study reviews noise mitigation measures for rail infrastructure in Europe, focusing on cost efficiency. It compares vehicle-related measures (like brake shoe retrofitting), track-related measures (like rail dampers), propagation path measures (like noise barriers), and receiver measures (like double glazing). The study confirms that rail freight retrofitting is the most cost-effective option, updating previous findings from the STAIRRS project with current data and life cycle cost assessments. Despite challenges in obtaining detailed cost data, the study reaffirms that retrofitting remains the preferred strategy for noise reduction.

  </div>
</div>
  </div>
</div>

----

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: space-around;">
  <div style="flex: 1; text-align: center; margin: 10px; border: 1px solid #ccc; padding: 10px;">
    <emb135|width=200>
  </div>
  <div style="flex: 1; text-align: center; margin: 10px; border: 1px solid #ccc; padding: 10px;">
    <emb116|width=200>
  </div>
</div>
 
----

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc139> 
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">FreightSimSilent</div>

<button class="btn btn-primary" type="button" data-toggle="collapse" data-target="#collapse12" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse12">Description</button>
<div class="collapse" id="collapse12">
  <div class="card card-body">

The application FreightSimSilent allows all cost-relevant parameters for retrofitting to K or LL brake blocks to be easily manipulated and displayed in diagrams spanning 20 years. This helps users make sound decisions and optimise different retrofitting conditions. The software was developed for UIC by Deutsche Bahn and the IT company join and share.
FreightSimSilent is available in four languages: English, French, German and a user-definable language. 

  </div>
</div>
  </div>
</div>

----

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc130> 
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">Rail Dampers, Acoustic Rail Grinding, Low Height Noise Barriers - 2012
SBB, UIC</div>

<button class="btn btn-primary" type="button" data-toggle="collapse" data-target="#collapse13" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse13">Description</button>
<div class="collapse" id="collapse13">
  <div class="card card-body">

The report explores various noise mitigation options for railways, highlighting both widely used methods like noise barriers and more controversial ones such as rail dampers, acoustic rail grinding, and low-height noise barriers. Due to limited testing opportunities, the UIC Network Noise collected data and experiences from different countries on these measures. The report details the basics of noise control, explains the controversial methods, and summarizes the collected experiences and feedback from UIC members and other European representatives. The information was gathered through requests sent in 2011 and 2012, with additional results from other sources.

  </div>
</div>
  </div>
</div>

----

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: space-around;">
  <div style="flex: 1; text-align: center; margin: 10px; border: 1px solid #ccc; padding: 10px;">
    <emb133|width=200>
  </div>
  <div style="flex: 1; text-align: center; margin: 10px; border: 1px solid #ccc; padding: 10px;">
    <emb134|width=200>
  </div>
</div>

----

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc156> 
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4"> The railway noise bonus - Discussion paper on the noise annoyance correction factor - 2010</div>
<button class="btn btn-primary" type="button" data-toggle="collapse" data-target="#collapse17" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse17">Description</button>
<div class="collapse" id="collapse17">
  <div class="card card-body">

When people are exposed to environmental noise, a range of adverse effects may occur. In case of excessive or incidental noise, people tend to complain. In daily life, people can be disturbed in their activities, such as working, communicating or sleeping. In the long turn, these effects may cause annoyance. Annoyance could affect health, because it may lead to irregular hormone secretion, stress, high blood pressure and cardiovascular problems.

Excessive noise during the night may disturb healthy sleep patterns and could lead to awakenings.

  </div>
</div>
  </div>
</div>
----

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc137> 
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">Noise differentiated track access charges, 2008</div>
<button class="btn btn-primary" type="button" data-toggle="collapse" data-target="#collapse19" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse19">Description</button>
<div class="collapse" id="collapse19">
  <div class="card card-body">

For further information about UIC’s publications on the implementation of noise related track access charges (NDTAC), please consult: [https://uic.org/sustainable-development/noise-and-vibration/noise-differentiated-track-access-charges->https://uic.org/sustainable-development/noise-and-vibration/noise-differentiated-track-access-charges]

  </div>
</div>
  </div>
</div>
----

<div style="display: flex; justify-content: space-around;">
  <div style="flex: 1; text-align: center; margin: 10px; border: 1px solid #ccc; padding: 10px;">
    <emb128|width=200>
  </div>
  <div style="flex: 1; text-align: center; margin: 10px; border: 1px solid #ccc; padding: 10px;">
    <emb138|width=200>
  </div>
</div>

----

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc129> 
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">Rail Freight Noise Abatement: A report on the state of the art</div>

<button class="btn btn-primary" type="button" data-toggle="collapse" data-target="#collapse22" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse22">Description</button>
<div class="collapse" id="collapse22">
  <div class="card card-body">

{{Executive summary}}
The EU supports railways, because they are the most sustainable means of transportation.
This, however, requires the railways to reduce noise, their most important environmental issue. Noise concern in the EU has led to the Environmental Noise Directive (END), which requires noise maps and actions plans for major railways as well as inside agglomerations. Railway noise emissions of new and upgraded vehicles have recently been limited by EU legislation...

 </div>
</div>
  </div>
</div>

----

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc3330> 
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">UIC Combatting curve squeal Phase 2 - State-of-the-art report - 2005</div>

<button class="btn btn-primary" type="button" data-toggle="collapse" data-target="#collapse23" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse23">Description</button>
<div class="collapse" id="collapse23">
  <div class="card card-body">

{{Curve squeal noise, 2005}}
Curve squeal is an intense tonal noise that may occur on curves or on switches. The high noise level causes annoyance for people living in the vicinity of a squealing railway track as well as for passengers waiting in stations with curves. The character of the noise is very intense with high frequencies (up to 10,000 Hz) and high amplitudes that can be up to 100 dB(A) in 10 m distance.

To answer to this problem, the UIC Combating Curve Squeal project was designed to find measures against the annoying high-pitched noise created during pass-bys of trains in certain curves. A first phase, completed in 2003, was aimed at analyzing existing knowledge and developing models while the second phase, described in the report below, intended to increase confidence in selected mitigation measures.
A selection of friction modifiers and water were tested on two different rigs and under field conditions in Switzerland, France and the UK. 
In conclusion, no optimal solutions could be found that would work under all circumstances. For each curve the trade-off between performance, dosage and costs must therefore be evaluated separately.

 </div>
</div>
  </div>
</div>

----

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc152> 
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">Status and Options for the Reduction of Noise Emission from the Existing European Rail Freight Wagon Fleet - 2004</div>

<button class="btn btn-primary" type="button" data-toggle="collapse" data-target="#collapse24" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse24">Description</button>
<div class="collapse" id="collapse24">
  <div class="card card-body">

This report investigates the status and options for retrofitting of the existing European rail freight fleet based on a study commissioned by the European Commission and jointly funded together with the railways (UIC and CER), the wagon owners (UIP and UIRR) and the manufacturers (UNIFE). AEA Technology has been commissioned as consultant, including the specific task of performing an independent third party assessment of the existing activities and results of the rail sector in the field of noise. 

 </div>
</div>
  </div>
</div>

----

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc158> 
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">Noise Creation Limits for Railways - 2002</div>

<button class="btn btn-primary" type="button" data-toggle="collapse" data-target="#collapse25" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse25">Description</button>
<div class="collapse" id="collapse25">
  <div class="card card-body">

This paper contains greater detail of the technical background to the UIC report “Noise Creation Limits for Railways: Main Report on the Railway’s Position”. This technical knowledge has been built up by the collective endeavour of acoustic experts from railways, universities and research institutes over a period of more than 30 years.

 </div>
</div>
  </div>
</div>

----

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc157> 
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">Noise creation limits for railways</div>

<button class="btn btn-primary" type="button" data-toggle="collapse" data-target="#collapse26" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse26">Description</button>
<div class="collapse" id="collapse26">
  <div class="card card-body">

{{Introduction}}
The UIC (International Union of Railways) has co-ordinated the activity of railways since 1922.
All the principal operating and infrastructure companies are members. For a number of years it has worked to co-ordinate its members’ efforts to minimise the impact of railway activities upon the environment. Among these impacts, the noise created by railway operations is of particular concern. Consequently UIC has played a central role over the past 30 years in co-ordinating the research activities of its members in the area of railway acoustics. This research work forms the foundations for this report, which sets out current knowledge of the phenomenon of railway noise and the potential of technical measures to mitigate it. The report also contains proposals for future achievable and affordable noise creation limits which are based on this knowledge.

 </div>
</div>
  </div>
</div>

----

<div class="row">
  <div class="col-md-3">
    <doc153> 
  </div>
  <div class="col-md-9">
<div class="h4">Railway Noise Research: Summary of Activities since 1990</div>

<button class="btn btn-primary" type="button" data-toggle="collapse" data-target="#collapse27" aria-expanded="false" aria-controls="collapse27">Description</button>
<div class="collapse" id="collapse27">
  <div class="card card-body">

{{Railway Noise Research - Summary of Activities since 1990 - 1998}}
This report describes the noise research carried out by ERRI and several European railways until 1998. It evaluates the options available to aim for a target of a 20 dB(A) noise reduction for freight vehicles compared with current levels in 1998. The paper concentrates on work that has, in the main, been funded by the UIC but also identifies certain national initiatives.
The summary indicates that a great deal of work has been carried out and a high level of knowledge has been accumulated to find effective solutions to reduce railway noise in its creation and reception.
There are still areas of research where work can be identified to further reduce railway noise but these need to be prioritized to meet strategic aims. However, social and legislative pressures will continue to determine that railways will need to concentrate further efforts on noise reduction techniques.

 </div>
</div>
  </div>
</div>

----

{{{UIC Focus Noise}}}

<body>
    <table border="1">
        <thead>
            <tr>
                <th>Year of publication</th>
                <th>Month</th>
                <th>Download PDF file</th>
            </tr>
        </thead>
        <tbody>
            <tr>
                <td>2014</td>
                <td>November</a></td>
                <td><doc127></td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>2014</td>
                <td>April</a></td>
                <td><doc124></td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>2013</td>
                <td>June</a></td>
                <td><doc126></td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>2012</td>
                <td>July</a></td>
                <td><doc125></td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>2010</td>
                <td>June</a></td>
                <td><doc123></td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>2009</td>
                <td>October</a></td>
                <td><doc122></td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>2009</td>
                <td>February</a></td>
                <td><doc121></td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>2008</td>
                <td>March</a></td>
                <td><doc120></td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
                <td>2007</td>
                <td>August</a></td>
                <td><doc119></td>
            </tr>
        </tbody>
    </table>
</body>
</html>


{{{Workshops}}}

If you missed the seminars or would like to keep the information in your archive, please take a look at these following links:
-* {{UIC Sustainability Action Week – UIC Railway Noise Days 2025: }}[https://uic.org/events/sustainability-action-week-2025->https://uic.org/events/sustainability-action-week-2025]
-* {{UIC Railway Noise Days 2023:}} [https://uic.org/events/uic-railway-noise-days-2023->https://uic.org/events/uic-railway-noise-days-2023]
Webinar replay: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/playlist?list=PLUdND40cgRldI78heH4XP84R94V5jr3Ub" class="btn btn-outline-danger" target="_blank">Youtube playlist <i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a>
-* {{Ideathon in Paris, 2022:}} [https://uic.org/events/ideathon-in-paris->https://uic.org/events/ideathon-in-paris]
-* {{UIC Railway Noise Days 2021:}} [https://uic.org/events/uic-railway-noise-days->https://uic.org/events/uic-railway-noise-days]
Webinar replay: <a href="https://youtube.com/playlist?list=PLUdND40cgRlftzGk3tHChuSz8LDyKDUU9" class="btn btn-outline-danger" target="_blank">Youtube playlist <i class="fas fa-external-link-alt"></i></a>
-* {{12th UIC Workshop on Noise and vibration:}} [https://uic.org/events/12th-uic-workshop-on-railway-noise-vibrations->https://uic.org/events/12th-uic-workshop-on-railway-noise-vibrations]
-* {{11th UIC Noise Workshop:}} [https://uic.org/events/11th-uic-noise-workshop->https://uic.org/events/11th-uic-noise-workshop]
-* {{10th UIC Noise Workshop:}} [https://uic.org/events/10th-uic-noise-workshop->https://uic.org/events/10th-uic-noise-workshop]]]>
            </texte>
            <group1>Sustainability;Environment;Noise;</group1>
	    <themes>19;20;131;</themes>
          				<images>
					doc131;doc4268;doc4269;doc4270;doc4271;doc4272;doc4273;doc4274;
				</images>
				<portfolio>
					doc116;doc118;doc119;doc120;doc121;doc122;doc123;doc124;doc125;doc126;doc127;doc128;doc129;doc130;doc133;doc134;doc135;doc136;doc137;doc138;doc139;doc1504;doc2486;doc2996;doc3011;doc3329;doc3330;doc3792;doc3793;
				</portfolio>
        </rubrique>
        
</rubriques>